motivators.com 2017-06-07

# Motivators Privacy Policy, Commitment to Data Security, Motivators Information

**Our Commitment To Privacy**

This privacy policy applies to www.motivators.com owned and operated by Motivators, Inc. (collectively "We", "Us" or "Our"). Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online and internal information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage ([www.Motivators.com](http://www.motivators.com/)) and at every point where personal information may be requested.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

**The Information We Collect**

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the Motivators website. These Pages are Secure. On some pages, you can order products, make requests, and register to receive material. The types of personal information collected at these pages are:  

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email Address
  * Phone Number
  * Credit/Debit Card Information
  * Shipper # information
  * Date of Birth (optional)
  * (etc)

On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you order a product online and want it sent directly to another recipient, you will need to submit the recipient's address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected are: 

  * Name
  * Address
  * Email Address
  * Phone Number

This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided.

**Tracking Technologies**

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Motivators, Inc. and our marketing partners, or analytics providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing these types of tracking technologies.

We use cookies to remember users' settings for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

**Log Files**

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data.

We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

**Local Storage Object (Flash)**

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as Flash to store preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as Flash to collect and store information.

To manage Flash LSOs please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

**Behavioral Advertising**

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

**The Way We Use Information**

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only to complete that order. We do not share information with outside third parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order or in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

We use the information you provide about someone else when placing an order only to ship the product and to confirm delivery. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order. This third party may contact us at [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

When an order is placed, you will receive an email order acknowledgement. We reveal only the last 5 digits of the card when confirming the order. ** Please do not email us credit card number information, as email is not secure.** If you do not feel comfortable entering your credit card information over the internet, please call 1-800-525-9600 and one of our representatives will be happy to help you.

When you register with our website you will receive updates on our new products and services. If you wish to be removed from this list, please send an email to [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com).

You may also receive periodic mailings from Motivators (i.e. catalogs, flyers). If you wish to be removed from this mailing list, please send an email to [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com)

We do not share your phone number with outside parties. Your phone number will be used to contact you regarding order information. Occasionally, we may contact you via phone to inform you of new products and special deals we are offering. If you do not wish to receive this information by phone, please contact [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com).

We do not share your email address with any outside parties.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Ways we will disclose your personal information: 

  * In certain situations, Motivators, Inc. may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. As required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * If Motivators, Inc. is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

We never use or share the personal information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses.

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our website and to share with advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our website, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out our registration form, but we would not disclose anything that could be used to identify those individuals.

**Our Commitment To Data Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com).

When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We are also protected by VeriSign, a service to assure that your information is kept secure. For information click here: [https://trustsealinfo.verisign.com/splash?form_file=fdf/splash.fdf&dn=secure.motivators.com&lang=en](https://trustsealinfo.verisign.com/splash?form_file=fdf/splash.fdf&dn=secure.motivators.com&lang=en)

**Our Commitment To Children's Privacy**

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 18, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 18. If we become aware that the child under 18 has provided us with personal information, we will delete their information immediately and terminate the child's account.

**Surveys**

From time-to-time, we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personal information from you. Participation in these surveys is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes.

**Customer Testimonials/Comments/Reviews**

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacy@motivators.com.

**Blogs**

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at privacy@motivators.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Alternatively, if you used a third party application to post such information, you can remove it, by either logging into the said application and removing the information or by contacting the appropriate third party application.

**Chat**

We use a chat feature to assist you with any questions you have while shopping on our website. If our chat feature is offline we will collect your name and email address so that we may reply to your request. By requesting your name and email address, we are able to follow up on any questions you may have after the chat has been completed.

**Accessing/Correcting Personal Information**

Upon request Motivators, Inc. will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or ask to have it removed from our blog or testimonial, or deactivate it by making the change on our member information page, by emailing our Customer Support at [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com), or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within a reasonable timeframe.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Motivators, Inc. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

**Social Media Widgets**

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Frames**

Some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to www.motivators.com.

**Data Retention**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Notification of Privacy Policy Changes**

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please 

  * call us at 1-800-525-9600
  * send us an email at [privacy@motivators.com](mailto:privacy@motivators.com)
  * send a letter to 123 Frost St. Suite 201 Westbury, NY 11590

By Visiting Motivators.com, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy notice.

This Privacy Policy has been in effect since 11/21/2016
